（ユウ）ここで　お別れです。
さようなら　桜満　集。
This is where we part.
Goodbye, Shu Ouma.
（涯）うっ　くっ…。
あぁ…！
This is why I can't leave you...
to your own devices...
だから　ほっとけないんだ
お前は…。
Gai...
（集）涯…。
A Void? That entire town?
（嘘界）ヴォイド？
あの街　全てが？
Yes. Roppongi Fort is a phantasm
given form by a single girl's heart.
（茎道）そう。
六本木フォートは→
１人の少女の心で形作られた
幻影なのだよ。
Mana Ouma, I assume?
（嘘界）桜満　真名ですね？
Here's the Void information I promised you.
（茎道）約束の
ヴォイドに関する情報だ。→
受け取りたまえ。
Take it.
（茎道）協力　感謝する。
だが　ここからは別料金だ。
I appreciate your cooperation.
But the fare you paid only gets you this far.
（嘘界）つれない人だ。
What a cold man.
うぅ…　あぁ…。
Don't tell me you're...
君は…　まさか！
So you finally remember?
You're as dense as ever...
やっと　思い出したか。
鈍いのは相変わらずだな　集。
...Shu.
ハッ！
君は…！
Who are you?!
So, everything that makes me whole
♪♪～
I'll now give to you
I'm yours
Say, there's lots of happiness
in this world, isn't there?
Someday, if we're together
Even if someone calls you a liar
And tries to hurt you with heartless words
Even if the world tries to make
you wear a crown of thorns
Without even trying to believe in you
I can take your side, and yours alone
I know that solitude, that pain
So, everything that makes me whole
I'll now give to you
rebirth
ようやくお出ましか
ダアトの墓守。
So you finally show yourself...
Daath grave keeper...
墓守？
"Grave keeper"?
（ユウ）修一郎が
とても頑張ったので→
Shuichiro worked so very hard
that we decided to cooperate.
われわれも
協力することにしたんです。
あっ…。
追え！　集！
Follow him... Shu...
They mean to... sacrifice Inori... to awaken Mana!
やつらは　いのりを　いけにえに
真名を目覚めさせる気だ。
真名…？
Mana?
うあぁぁぁぁ！
いのりを　どこへ！？
Where are you taking Inori?!
Shu!
（祭）集！
What's going on?
（綾瀬）「何が起こってるの！？」
いのり！！
Inori!
Shu Ouma, if you're that
determined to come with us,
（ユウ）桜満　集。
どうしても来るというなら→
全て思い出してからに
してください。→
please do so after you've remembered everything.
君が　自ら封じた　真名の記憶を。
All the memories of Mana
that you yourself sealed away...
うわぁぁぁぁぁ！
（真名）集。　もういいわよ。→
Shu. All set.
目を開けて　集。
Open your eyes now, Shu.
わぁ…！
すごいね　真名お姉ちゃん！
This is amazing, Mana!
（真名）でしょ？
お姉ちゃんの秘密の場所よ。
Isn't it? This is your big sister's secret place.
You're the only one I'll tell.
集にだけ教えてあげる。
うわぁ…！
あれ？　何だろ…。
Huh? What's that?
Is he dead?
死んでるの？
（心臓マッサージをする音）
（せき）
大丈夫？　聞こえる？
Are you okay?
Can you hear me?
俺　集。　桜満　集。
I'm Shu. Shu Ouma.
（真名）私は　桜満　真名。
あなたは？
I'm Mana Ouma.
And you are?
Maybe he doesn't understand.
分かんないのかな？
名前だよ。　な　ま　え。
We're asking your name. Your name!
それは…。
Well...
（真名）トリトン。
えっ？
"Triton."
You came from the sea. So you're Triton.
海から来たんだもの。
あなたはトリトン。
Isn't that a great name?
すてきな名前でしょ？
《そう。　あの日　僕は→
That's right... My big sister Mana
and I met a boy that day.
姉の真名と共に
１人の少年に出会ったんだ》
That boy Mana called "Triton"...
《真名がトリトンと呼んだ
あの少年　涯に》
Gai.
《そして　僕らは
一つの夏を共に過ごした》
And we spent a summer together.
《ロストクリスマスの年　みんなが笑顔で過ごせた最後の夏を》
The year of Lost Christmas...
The last summer we could all spend smiling.
ねえ　ホントに跳ぶの？
Hey, are you serious about jumping?
大丈夫だよ。　俺を信じろよ。
It'll be fine! Believe in me!
You're next! Come on!
次はお前だ　来いよ！
あっ！　あぁぁ！
See? You did it.
なっ！　できただろ？
うん！
Yeah.
《そして　同じ時間を過ごすうち→
And as we spent time together,
彼は　僕にとって
親友と呼べる存在になったんだ》
he became special to me enough
to call him a "best friend."
《優しくて大好きだった
お姉ちゃん　真名がいて→
I had Mana, the gentle big sister
I loved, and my best friend Gai...
親友である涯がいて→
That was the happiest,
most fun summer of my life.
僕の人生で　一番楽しくて
幸せだった夏》
So why... why did I forget?
《なのに　なぜ…》
《なぜ　僕は
忘れてしまったんだろう？》
About Gai, and Mana too.
《涯のことも　真名のことも》
（茎道）気が付いたか。
Awake now?
Where are we?
ここは…？
あっ！
いのり！
Inori!
くっ…！
何なんですか　これ！？
いのりを返してください！
What is this?! Please, give back Inori!
（茎道）この少女は　もともと→
This girl has never been more
than an "instance body" we created
われわれが　真名と意思の疎通を
図るためにつくった→
to use as an interface
for communication with Mana.
インターフェース用
インスタンスボディー。→
返すという言葉は当たらないな。
The words "give back" aren't really appropriate.
"Created"?
つくった？
And as the first person who ever
touched the "rock that started it all,"
（茎道）そして　真名は
はじまりの石に最初に触れた→
アポカリプスウイルスの
第１感染者。→
Mana was the first one infected with
the Apocalypse Virus: in other words, Eve.
すなわち　イヴ。→
肉体を失った彼女の魂は
今　新たな体に注がれ→
Her soul which had lost its body
is now being poured into a new body,
われわれの手で　再び
この世に降り立とうとしている。→
and thanks to our labors, she is
about to set foot in this world again.
彼女の復活は
ロストクリスマスの再来。→
Her resurrection will mark
the second coming of Lost Christmas.
アポカリプスが
世界中で猛威を振るうだろう。→
The Apocalypse Virus shall
run rampant over all the Earth.
私は　その証人に
ならねばならんのだ。→
I must bear witness to that event.
ダアトは　お前に
何か期待しているようだが→
Daath seems to have some hopes for you,
but if you ask me, you're just a child.
私に言わせれば
ただの小僧にすぎん。→
So stand back...
黙って　そこで見ていろ。
...and watch quietly.
いのりーっ！！
Inori!
（ユウ）邪魔をしてはなりません。
You mustn't interfere.
これから　彼が　いのりを介して
真名にプロポーズします。
He's about to propose to Mana through Inori.
プロポーズ…？
Propose?
彼女が選ぶ伴侶が→
You see, her chosen partner
will become the progenitor of
the next generation, the new human race.
次代の新たな人類の
始祖となるのです。→
わがままなイヴも　石を使えば
コントロールできるようになりますから。
Even selfish Eve can be controlled,
if you use the stone.
（ユウ）２人の未来に
祝福を捧げてもらえますね？
I trust we can count on you
to bless their future together?
This can't be...
そんなバカな…！
結婚？
（真名）そうよ。
Marry?
Yep. If I marry someone, will you be lonely, Shu?
もしも　私が誰かと結婚したら
寂しい？　集。
誰と？
誰かよ。
Marry who?
Someone! Maybe Triton.
トリトンかもしれない。
トリトン！？　駄目だよ　そんな…。
Triton?! You can't do that!
フフッ。　冗談よ　集。
I'm joking, Shu.
トリトンなんかと
結婚しないわ。→
I'd never marry that guy.
He looked at me with adult eyes, you know.
あいつ　私のことを
大人の目で見たのよ。→
いやらしい目で。
気持ちが悪い。
Leering eyes.
It makes me sick.
分からないや。
I don't know.
But you can look at me with adult eyes, Shu.
でも　集は
大人の目で見ていいのよ。
お姉ちゃん？
Sis?
好きよ　集。
I love you, Shu.
あ…。
ウイルスでしょ。
It's the virus, isn't it?
その斑点は
あの石からのウイルスだ。
Those spots are from the virus in that rock.
父さんが言ってた。
それは人を狂わすって。
Dad said it makes people go crazy.
What do you want to do with Shu, Mana?
真名は　集をどうしたいの？
≪（雷鳴）
死んでいた　あなたを
生き返らせたのは　私。
I'm the one who brought you back from the dead.
だから　あなたは私のもの。
That means you're mine.
私が自由にしていい。
そうでしょ？
I can do whatever I want with you.
Right?
ま…　真名…？
M-Mana...
私はね　集と結ばれるの。
誰にも邪魔はさせないわ。
I am going to tie the knot with Shu.
And I won't let anyone get in my way. Got that?
分かった？
≪（雷鳴）
ねえ　集。　約束よ。
Hey, Shu.
Promise me...
私と　結婚して。
...that you'll marry me.
O ye chosen fittest pair,
perform the coming together of blood
（ユウ）「なんじら
選ばれし適者の一対よ。→
新たな種を紡ぐ　血の交わりを…」
that shall shape the new race.
（いのり）んっ。
やめろぉぉ！！
Stop it!
（真名）「駄目よ　集」
Bad Shu.
You have no right to get angry.
（真名）
「怒る資格なんか　ないのよ」→
「あなたは
私を遠ざけたじゃない」→
You shunned me, didn't you?
You wrecked me back then, didn't you? Shu.
「あのとき
私を損なったじゃない　集」
What do you mean?
何のこと？
（真名）「何も覚えてないの？
忘れちゃった？」→
You don't remember anything? Did you forget?
I'll have to punish you, then.
「じゃあ　お仕置き」
うっ…　うわぁぁぁ！
Are you okay, Shu?!
（綾瀬）「無事？　集！」
綾瀬…！
Ayase!
This is why I can't leave you to your own devices!
だから　お前は　ほっとけないんだ。
涯！　傷は！？
急所は逃れた。
Gai! What about your wounds?!
He didn't hit any vital organs.
The cancer crystals saved me.
キャンサーの結晶に救われた。
（茎道）恙神　涯。
俺は　この時を待っていたんだ。
Gai Tsutsugami.
I've been waiting for this moment.
あんたと　そして　真名と
対峙できる　この瞬間を！
The moment I can confront you... and Mana!
（嘘界）私が隠し撮りしたものは→
My hidden camera footage was as staticky
this time as when I shot the Void,
ヴォイドを撮ったときと同じように
ノイズだらけでしたが→
鮮明に見えますね。
but yours seems crystal clear.
（春夏）
セフィラの試作フィルターよ。
It's Sephirah's prototype filter.
（春夏）
なぜ　私たちを通してくれたの？
Why did you let us through?
アリーナから
追い出されてしまったのでね。→
I was booted out of the arena, you see.
ささやかな意地悪です。
This is my little way of picking on him.
だが　もう遅い。
運命は変わらぬ。
You're too late, though.
Destiny can't be changed.
Shu! Run!
集！　走れ！
≪（衝撃音）
（綾瀬）「集！」
Shu!
（綾瀬）「うあぁぁぁ！」
鶫！　緊急ベイルアウト！
（綾瀬）「涯！　まだ戦えます！」
Tsugumi! Emergency bailout!
Gai, I can still fight!
（茎道）フン。
（ユウ）らせんの契りを
今　ここに。
Spiral nuptial vows, here and now.
Remember, Shu.
集　思い出せ。
あの日の出来事を。
Some part of you must
remember what happened that day.
お前は覚えているはずだ。
あの日？
"That day"?
ロストクリスマスだ。
Lost Christmas.
２０２９年１２月。
December, 2029.
俺たちは　お前の新しい母
桜満　春夏に連れられ→
We were in Tokyo.
Your new mother,
Haruka Ouma, had brought us here.
東京に来ていた。
そして　１２月２４日。
And on December 24th, I asked you
to come to a church in Roppongi.
俺は　お前を
六本木の教会に呼び出した。
お前の知らない真名について
話すためだ。
I wanted to talk to you about
the Mana you didn't know.
≪（ドアの開く音）
しかし　そこに来たのは→
But the one who came...
お前ではなかった。
...wasn't you.
（真名）《メリークリスマス》
《ありがとう》
Merry Christmas.
Thank you.
Open it.
（真名）《開けて》
（真名）《トリトンは
私のナイトなんでしょ？》→
You're my knight, aren't you Triton?
So keep on protecting me.
《だから
これからも　私を守って》
（真名）
《あの星を狙って　撃って》
Take a shot at that star.
《ハッ…！》
《うん》
≪（銃声）
Triton.
（真名）《トリトン。
私は　あなたが好きだったのよ》
I loved you, you know.
《嘘よ》
Just kidding.
≪《トリトン？》
Triton?
《トリトン！？　どうしたの？》
Triton! What happened?
《トリトン！》
（真名）《さあ　取って。　集》
Triton?!
Take this, Shu.
《私たちの遺伝子で
新しい世界をつくりましょう》
Let's use our genes to make a new world.
《えっ？》
（真名）《大丈夫。　怖がらないで》
It's okay. Don't be scared.
《楽しいこと　しましょ。　集》
Let's do something fun together, Shu.
《来るなよ→
Stay away from me... you monster!
この　化け物！！》
《あっ…。　あっ！》
《お…　お姉ちゃん！》
Sis?
No!
《嫌っ！！》
Sorry.
（真名）《ごめんね》
《ごめんね。　集…》
Sorry, Shu.
Don't be scared.
《怖がらないで》→
《お姉ちゃんも怖いのよ！！》
Your big sister's scared, too!
《あっ！》
《このままじゃ
私が私でなくなる…！》
At this rate... I'll become someone who isn't me!
（女性）《うわぁ！》
（男性）《うわぁ！》
（男性）《うおぉ！》
そして　真名は→
And so Mana ended up destroying
herself with her own out-of-control power.
暴走する力で
自分自身を壊してしまった。
そうだ。
Yes... Mana looked to us for help that day...
あのとき　真名は
僕らに助けを求め→
僕らは
それに応えることができなかった。
And we couldn't give it to her.
だから　涯は　こう言ったよね。
So Gai, you said...
《僕は　強くなる》
I'm going to get stronger.
《さよなら》
Goodbye.
忘れていた。
I'd forgotten.
僕は　忘れることで
自分を守っていたんだ。
I was protecting myself by forgetting!
集。　今なら分かるだろう？
Shu. You can tell right now, can't you?
俺たちには　やるべきことがある。
We have something we need to do.
真名の心を取り戻すこと。
そうだ。
Get Mana's heart back.
That's right.
やつらに　無理やり
目覚めさせられた真名を→
They awakened her against her will,
and we're going to put her to sleep again!
もう一度
俺たちの手で眠らせるんだ。
Use the Void's power to
consign her bad will to oblivion!
あいつの悪意を
ヴォイドの力で葬れ！
記憶の鎖が解け
新しい王のモードに入ったか。
Memory's shackles are undone,
and you're in new king mode, eh, Shu Ouma?
桜満　集。
もう時間がない。
取り出せ　集。　俺の心を。
Time is running out. Draw out my heart, Shu.
And then give me the Void!
そして
取り出したヴォイドを俺に渡せ。
The way you are right now,
I know you can do it!
今の　お前なら　できるはずだ！
Draw it out without letting go of my hand.
この手を離さず　取り出せ。
うわああ！！
これが　涯の…。
This is... Gai's...
集　走れ。
Run, Shu.
真名の所へ向かう俺を
援護するんだ。
You're going to cover me while I head for Mana.
分かった。
Got it.
行くぞ。
Here we go.
あっ…。
ああっ…！
いのり！
（真名）「集…。　誰を呼んでるの？」
Inori!
Who are you calling, Shu?
涯！
Gai!
あっ！
ヴォイドを
強制的に出現させるヴォイド！？
A Void that forces other Voids to manifest?!
人の心を引き出す銃か！
A gun that draws out people's hearts, then...
うあああーっ！！
涯！　行って！
ああ！
Gai, go!
Right!
Stop!
待て！　おっ！
引きなさい　修一郎。
Stand down, Shuichiro.
You failed.
あなたは失敗しました。
（茎道）うっ！
♪♪～
≪（足音）
涯！
Gai!
俺ごと　真名を刺せ！　集！
Stab Mana right through me, Shu.
どのみち　俺は助からん！
I'm a dead man either way. So...
だから…。
でも！
But...
集。
Shu, what do I look like to you right now?
今　お前には　俺がどう見える？
えっ？
子供のころのお前は
決断力があって→
As a child you were decisive,
and brave, and... strong...
勇敢で　強くて…。
俺は　お前のようになりたいと
思っていた。
I wanted to become like you.
涯！　何を…。
Gai! What are you?!
お前は　いつだって　俺になれる…。
You can become me whenever
you want. Just like I became you.
俺が　お前になれたように…。
あとは　１人でやってみろ。
Do the rest on your own.
さあ　早くしろ！
Come on. Hurry up!
くっ…。
うわあああああ！！
Gai!
涯！
♪♪～
集。
Shu...
What did you say that day?
あっ…。
トリ…　トン？
Tri... ton?
真名。
やっと　お前に届いた。
Words that'll never be heard flutter in the air
Mana... I finally reached you.
Even though I know better,
I can't help making another
Gai! Gai!
涯！　涯っ！！
Hopeless wish today
♪♪～
Keep holding my hand tight and don't let go
Tell me you'll stay with me
涯は　きっと
満足してる。
I'm sure Gai is satisfied.
聞こえたの。
I could hear him saying "thank you."
Your hand in mine was warm and kind
「ありがとう」って。
（泣き声）
♪♪～